尽管你们的毕业证书相当管用 记住：
Although your diplomas are equally specific, remember:
你们是独自去闯世界
you are all going out into the world as individuals.
加油 加油 加油
Go, go, go.
是我 全新的大学公主毕业生
it's me. Brand-new college graduate-slash-princess.
一切都会好的 因为他们希望能有一个孩子
It must be going well, because they are now expecting a baby.
莉莉还是老样子 一如既往的制造麻烦
Lilly's remained the same, as she continues to cause turmoil,
自从他和他的乐队全国巡回演出后 我们现在只是朋友
we're just friends now, as he went off to tour the country with his band.
看看窗外 欢迎回到基诺维亚
Look out the window, and welcome back to Genovia.
哦 是的 我美丽的基诺维亚
Oh, there it is. My beautiful Genovia.
当然 能够回来我很激动 但是也有一点紧张
Of course, I'm completely excited to be going back, but I'm also a bit nervous.
基诺维亚一号已经着陆
Genovia One has landed.
奶奶克拉丽斯今年年底将从女皇的位置退下来
Grandma Clarisse will step down by the end of this year as queen,
我知道我在学校里学的是外交和政治 但是...
I know I studied diplomacy and political science at school, but...
但是奶奶会教我 在她认为我准备好了的时候会让我接任
But Grandma's going to help me, and I'll take over when she thinks I'm ready.
在这期间 我会住在一个像童话般漂亮的宫殿里
In the meantime, I'm going to live in a beautiful palace like in a fairy tale,
那样会很恐怖或是什么的吗?
Is that scary or what?
好了 或许胖路易会帮助我的
Well, maybe Fat Louie can give me some help.
公主 欢迎回家
Welcome home, Princess.
在我的童话里 有件沮丧的事情就是我从未恋爱过
The one downer in my fairy tale is I've never been in love.
不管怎么样 今晚是我21岁的生日晚会
However, this evening is my 21st-birthday party,
我必须同基诺维亚所有符合条件的单身汉跳舞
I have to dance with all the eligible bachelors in Genovia.
或许今晚我能遇见我的白马王子
So maybe I'll meet my Prince Charming tonight.
女皇要来了
The queen is coming.
她要有一个双门的入口
She'll have a double-door entrance.
她已经到大厅了
She's in the foyer.
真漂亮
Beautiful.
但是你迟到了 殿下
But you're late, Your Majesty.
当然
Of course.
你们好 朋友们
Greetings, good friends.
很高兴今晚你们能来这里
I am delighted to welcome you here this evening.
好的
good.
你们很多人应该记得鲁柏特国王和我的 孙女米娅公主
Many of you will remember King Rupert's and my granddaughter, Princess Mia.
鲁柏特国王 愿他长眠
King Rupert. May he rest in peace.
敬米娅公主
To Princess Mia.
哦 我不会说希腊语
I don't speak Greek.
你显然也不会说英语
And you obviously don't speak English.
一 二 三 一 二 三
One, two, three. One, two, three.
对不起
Sorry.
我想死你了
I've missed you.
你还好吗?
Are you all right?
我还活着 殿下
I'll survive, Your Highness.
都是我脚的错 对不起
The fault was entirely my own. I apologize.
你确认你不想换保险执照和保险证吗?
Are you sure you don't want to exchange licenses and proof of insurance?
不 不 这些鞋子只是有点大
No, no. These shoes were a little big anyway.
慢慢的膨胀会使它们更舒服的
The swelling should help them fit better.
嘿 看这个男的
Hey, get a load of this guy.
摇动 摇动
Shimmy shimmy.
可以吗?
May l?
米娅 我喜欢别人叫我米娅
Mia. I like to be called Mia.
那么你是?
And you are?
我很高兴我的笨拙没有影响到你的舞步
I'm very glad to see that my clumsiness hasn't affected your dancing.
对不起 我刚才踩到你的脚了
I'm sorry I stepped on your foot.
你可以任何时候踩它
You can step on my foot anytime.
轮到雅克王子了
It is Prince Jacques' turn.
殿下
Your Highness.
他是一个早熟的王子
He's a very precocious prince.
他擦了须后水 好让别人认为他很成熟
He wears aftershave to make people think that he's older.
可以和你耳语几句吗?
May I blow in your ear?
你够得着吗?
Can you reach it?
公主 你应该会见一些国会的人
Princess, there's someone from parliament you should meet.
夏洛特 这里有多少国会的人?
Charlotte, how many members of parliament are there?
只剩下两个 殿下
Only two left, Your Highness.
哦 殿下 对不起 这只是一次意外
Oh, Your Highness, pardon me, I am so sorry. It was only an accident.
没事 没事 没有受伤 没有弄脏 没有撞到
It's fine, it's fine. No harm, no foul, no bruise.
非常感谢
Thank you so much.
你应该注意些 高贵的殿下
You should be more careful, Your Royal Highness.
有人可能会把这个拿走的
Somebody might try to take that away from you.
哦 希望不会 不过还是要谢谢你的帮助
Oh, I hope not. But thank you so much for all your help.
嘿 怎么样了?
Hi. How's it going?
好了 去干你们的事吧
Enough bowing. Back to your chores.
殿下一个小时内会在王宫见您
Her Majesty will meet you in one hour at the throne room.
我能去看看皇宫的其他地方吗?
can I explore the palace a little bit?
当然
Of course.
的确 我们都认识到了 子爵
Indeed, we are well aware of this, Viscount.
我指的不是米娅公主
It was not Princess Mia to whom I was referring.
你好？
Hello?
好极了
Nice.
有人吗?
Hello?
什么?
What?
我的侄子 德弗里奥克斯亲王
My nephew, Lord Devereaux.
请你再说一遍？
I beg your pardon?
我侄子的母亲是我夫人的姐姐
My nephew's mother was my wife's sister.
因此殿下 我很高兴的说 我的侄子准备接替他的位置
Therefore, Your Majesty, I am pleased to say that my nephew is ready to take his place
闭嘴
Shut up.
你说什么?
I beg your pardon?
但是米娅公主不是王室的第一继承人吗?
But isn't Princess Mia first in line to ascend the throne?
并不是这样的
Not yet.
我们从没有执行过那样的法律
We have never enforced that law.
一个男人就不必在当上国王之前结婚了
A man doesn't have to marry to be king.
我的意思是 这是21世纪了 看在上帝的份上
I mean, this is the 21 st century, for heaven's sake.
我的孙女应该拥有和其他男人同样的权力
My granddaughter should be given the same rights as any man.
对!
Yeah!
基诺维亚不应该要女皇 以免她会陷进婚姻的束缚中
Genovia shall have no queen lest she be bound in matrimony.
帕利莫阁下?
Lord Palimore?
那是过去300年的基诺维亚法律
That is the law of Genovia for the last 300 years.
米娅公主没有资格统治 因为她没有结婚
Princess Mia is not qualified to rule because she is unmarried.
请宽恕我 殿下
Forgive me, Your Majesty.
什么? 不行
What? No.
60天?
60 days?
30天
30 days.
国会怎么能让我在30天内就谈恋爱? 这就像...
How could parliament expect me to fall in love in 30 days? It's like...
不行
No.
包办婚姻是我唯一的选择
An arranged marriage is my only choice.
什么人能够同意这种包办婚姻的呢?
What kind of person agrees to an arranged marriage?
你同意了这个包办婚姻
You agreed to an arranged marriage.
它肯定会很壮观
And it turned out quite splendidly.
我肯定 奶奶 但是
I'm sure, Grandma, but...
我梦想爱情 但不沉迷于此
I dream of love, not fondness.
这不公平
This is so unfair.
阿米莉娅
Amelia.
勇气不是逃避恐惧
Courage is not the absence of fear,
我坚信 作为一个统治者 我能有一些机会做一些改变
I'm sure I want my chance to make a difference as a ruler.
这就像一个真正的女皇在说话
Spoken like a true queen.
哦 我的孩子 一个拥有基诺维亚血统的孩子
You, my boy, a true-born Genovian.
你应该成为我们的国王
You should be our king.
我同意
I agree.
但是 我们怎么才可以做到呢?
But how can we make it happen?
给我一枝镖
Give me one of your arrows.
我给你表演个从一个意大利老哲学家那学来的把戏
I'm going to show you a trick that I learned from an old ltalian philosopher.
我能让这只镖每次都击中靶心
I can make this dart hit the bull's-eye every time.
是的 但那是在作弊
Yes, but that is cheating.
你说对了
You've got it.
是的 殿下
Yes, Your Majesty.
我知道莱昂内尔是首相的侄子
I know Lionel is the prime minister's nephew
他整个夏天一直在做实习医师
and he's interning for the summer
我不知道你是否见过我们的女管家考特太太
I don't know if you've met Mrs. Kout, our housekeeper,
我正在调查奥莉维亚背景
I'm doing a background check on Olivia.
这个房间的每个人都可以优先排除
Everybody in this room has high-priority clearance.
当然 当然
Of course, of course.
我很愿意为你挡一颗子弹
I would gladly take a bullet for you.
哦 真勇敢
Oh, how brave.
很多实习医师都不愿帮我拿茶
Most interns don't even want to fetch me my tea.
车已经备好了 女士
The limousine is at the gates, madam.
子爵没有来 只来了他的侄子
The viscount is not staying, just the nephew.
乔瑟夫 我希望你能够保护他 并且时刻盯住他
Joseph, I want you to protect him and keep your eye on him at all times.
这样欢迎子爵和他的侄子可以吗?
So is this all right to welcome the viscount and his nephew?
非常合适 非常漂亮
Very appropriate. And pretty.
我不敢相信国会邀请了这个男的
I can't believe parliament invited the guy
哦 不 国会并没有邀请他
Oh, no, parliament didn't invite him.
是我邀请的
I did.
什么...
What...
我建议把他挂在我们的后花园
I offered to have him hung by his toes in our courtyard.
在乘客老死之前 你应该打开门
You just have to open the door before the passenger dies of old age.
我不想对这个家伙太好 你知道吗?
I just so don't want to be nice to this guy, you know?
哦 你见过他吗?
Ah, well, have you met him?
我们要表现的很优雅和高贵
We will present ourselves with grace and poise.
殿下
Your Majesty.
尼古拉斯 很高兴认识你
Nicholas. We are delighted to make your acquaintance.
殿下 这是我的荣幸
Your Majesty, the pleasure is all mine.
非常感谢您邀请我住在皇宫里
And thank you so much for inviting me to stay at the palace.
让我来介绍我的孙女米娅
May I present my granddaughter Mia.
殿下
Your Highness.
米娅 你能来迎接一下我们的客人吗?
Mia, would you care to welcome our guest?
尼古拉斯亲王
Lord Nicholas.
她总是那样
She always does that.
当然
Of course.
她正在学习弗拉门戈舞
She's training to be a flamenco dancer.
您能解释一下刚才发生在外面的事情吗？
Would you care to explain what was going on out there?
对不起
Sorry.
实际上 我已经见过尼古拉斯亲王了
I, have met Lord Nicholas, actually.
现在我觉得我真是太笨了
I feel so stupid right now.
现在 如果你和我一起来 我要给你看一些东西
Now, if you'll come with me, I have something to show you.
谢谢 厨师们
Thank you, culinary people.
我很快回来
I'll be back.
你房间的终于布置好了
The renovations for your suite are finally finished.
这是你自己真正的房间
This is your very own suite.
哦 奶奶
Oh, Grandma.
这里太美了
This is very nice.
好的
Good.
我们刚铺好床
We just made the bed.
这太酷了
This is so cool.
这儿还有
There's more.
好的
OK.
我有自己的商场了
I have my own mall.
哦 多漂亮的鞋子啊
Ooh, very nice shoes.
奶奶 你觉得怎么样?
What do you think? Grandma?
我在这
I'm here.
我为你特别挑选了这些订做的皇冠宝石
I had a selection of the crown jewels brought out for you.
它们可以帮你在恰当的时间里显示出杰出的判断力
They're yours to borrow, with great discretion, at appropriate times.
现在 让你看看最让你吃惊的东西
Now for the best surprise of all.
很高兴见到你
I'm so glad to see you.
如果他不合格 为什么他在这些画面里?
If he's not eligible, why is he included in these pictures?
下一个
Next.
太老了
Too old.
太年轻了
Too young.
像他那样的一些人?
Someone like him?
对 就是像他那样的人
Yes. Someone very much like him.
我们现在在一个莫斯小镇的微风和煦的海滩上
Here we are at the breezy seashore village of Mertz.
两位恋人在这样好的天气里开始了首次外出散步
And our two lovers have perfect weather for their first public outing.
哦 他们正在向我们招手
Oh, they're waving at us.
我抓到它了
I got it.
我们去喝点茶 怎么样?
Shall we have some tea?
我认为你可能比我更笨手笨脚
I think you might be clumsier than me.
哦 打的好
Oh, good shot.
只想要一份持久的爱
I want a love that will last
在过去200年里 我们家族的每个婚姻都是包办的...
Every marriage in my family for the past 200 years has been arranged...
这曾经是我曾祖母的订婚戒指
It was my great-grandmother's engagement ring.
她和我曾祖父结婚了57年了
She and my great-grandfather were married for 57 years.
所以 我...
So l...
哦 天啊 是一个戒指
Oh, my goodness. It was a ring.
他刚才向她求婚了
A royal proposal has been made.
爱情鸟到处飞翔
Fly the lovebirds.
舅舅 虽然我不想承认 但是你错了
Uncle, I hate to say this, but you were wrong.
米娅公主已经成功的在一个星期内找到他的丈夫了
Princess Mia has managed to find a husband within a week.
米娅不会喜欢包办婚礼的
Mia cannot possibly be happy with the idea of an arranged marriage.
你的任务是去勾引她
Your task is to romance her.
让她看看真正的爱情应该是什么
Show her what a real relationship could be like.
一种充满火热和激情的爱情
A relationship filled with heat and passion.
等待30天过后 皇冠就是我们的了
And the 30-day deadline expires, and the throne is ours.
这是他最大的心愿
It was his dearest wish.
我不记得他曾经那样对我说过
I don't recall him ever mentioning that to me.
但你一定记得他给你起的谁的名字 是吗?
But you do remember who he named you after, don't you?
是的 尼古拉斯爷爷
Yes. Grandfather Nicholas.
不 不 不 不 尼古拉斯・马基雅弗利
No, no, no, no. Niccolo Machiavelli.
是的 谢谢
Yes. Thank you.
谢谢
Thank you.
安德鲁的飞机刚刚起飞
Andrew's plane just took off.
他说等他一到伦敦就立刻给你打电话
He said he'd call as soon as he arrives in London.
我正在躲我的女仆
I'm hiding from my lady's maids.
但是我很好 很好
But I'm fine, I'm fine.
实际上 正好相反 我已经开始喜欢我的戒指了
Actually, on the contrary. I was just admiring my ring.
这是安德鲁的奶奶的
It was Andrew's grandmother's.
你也看到了 他真的很浪漫
You know, he really is so romantic.
对不起 你是不是有什么话想对我说?
I'm sorry, is there something you wanted to say to me?
不 不
No, no.
你是个用大脚踩我的人
You are the one who stomped on me with your big feet.
大脚?
Big feet?
布丽奇特 我找到她了
Brigitte, I found her.
啊 布丽奇塔
Uh, Brigitta.
好吧 你和我的大脚一起跳过舞
Well, you know, you danced with my big feet.
请原谅我 当时我可能有些失礼了
Please pardon me, I just had a momentary lapse of good manners.
你想知道你还干了些什么吗?
Do you want to know what else you were doing,
我将亲自去看看舞厅
I'll go look in the ballroom myself.
好的
All right.
请原谅我的打扰 殿下 德瑞福克斯亲王
Please forgive the intrusion, Your Highness, Lord Devereaux.
她具备女皇的素质吗?
Does she have the makings of a queen?
她还年轻 但我一直都相信她
she's young, but I've always believed in her.
婚礼的请贴都已经发出去了
The wedding invitations have been sent out.
你知道 她一开始很主动
She's very set on it, you know.
克拉丽斯 亲爱的 先忘掉婚礼吧
Clarisse, my dear. Forget the wedding for a moment.
我认为是时候让我们的关系浮出水面了
I think it's time we bring our friendship out of the shadows.
是的 亲爱的 尽管这里不合适 可是我还是想说
Yes, my dear. I would kneel if it weren't for my knee replacement.
乔瑟夫 还有婚礼需要筹备
Joseph, there's a wedding to be planned.
在不到30天里 米娅需要赢得基诺维亚人民的心
Mia needs to win over the people of Genovia, all in less than 30 days.
或许是时候考虑一下你自己的感情了
Perhaps it's time to consider the duty you have to yourself.
克拉丽斯
Clarisse...
亲爱的 请考虑一下
My darling, please think about it. Please.
我会的
I will.
公主日记 我的女皇旅程将继续 惊喜 惊喜
Dear diary. My queen lessons continue. Surprise, surprise.
它代表燃烧永恒不灭的火焰
It's symbolic for lighting my own eternal flame.
对不起
Sorry.
对不起 我很抱歉 我就迟到了一点
Sorry, I'm sorry. I am almost in time though.
好了 对不起 抓住了 我抓住了
OK, sorry, got it, I got it.
知道吗？ 我很好 没问题
You know what? I'm OK. I'm fine.
那么...
So...
起来 起来 我们仅仅只有10分钟来学习用这个交流
Get up. Get up. We only have about ten minutes in which to communicate this.
你在耍你的奶奶吗?
Are you sassing your grandma?
我从没有耍过你 奶奶
I would never sass you, Grandma.
这也是一种让人生气的方式
This is also a way of showing you're annoyed.
这是献给您的
This is for your table.
谢谢
Thank you.
谢谢 殿下
Thank you, Your Majesty.
您干的很好 他们都崇拜您
You do this so well. They just adore you.
这是古老的基诺维亚传统的一部分
It's part of an ancient Genovian tradition.
即使你不能提供帮助 你也要表现出你很关心你的子民
Even if you can't help, you have to show the people you care.
我们会看到你的奖学金申请表
We will review your scholarship application,
哦 谢谢 殿下
Oh, merci, Your Majesty.
这是我的孙女 米娅公主
May I present my granddaughter, Princess Mia.
小心
Be careful.
在王宫里 有只鸡出了点状况
We have a chicken situation in the throne room.
米娅
Mia.
嗯?
Yeah?
公主不应该去追一只鸡
A princess never chases a chicken.
整个宫廷都将被检阅 也包括军队
The whole court will be watching, plus the troops.
在骑马的时候 我要表现的很高雅
I also have to be ladylike while riding sidesaddle.
当我在你这个年龄的时候 我也不能骑马
I couldn't ride sidesaddle either when I was your age,
荷比是我的同伴 他来了
Herbie is my riding companion. Here he is.
荷比
Herbie.
我们的祖先知道一些小诀窍 是吗?
Our ancestors knew a thing or two, right?
你用你的裙子挡住它 那么没有人会怀疑
You just drape your skirt over it and nobody suspects a thing.
桑迪 很容易被蛇吓到
Sandy, gets easily spooked by snakes.
那么 让我们弄点真正的惊吓 如何?
So let's get it really spooked, shall we?
这是条假蛇
This is a fake snake.
我是尼克 马布雷子爵的侄子
I'm Nick. Viscount Mabrey's nephew.
哦 正在设法登上王座的家伙
Ah, the chap who's trying to stage the palace coup.
很荣幸
Pleasure.
我喜欢所有戴头盔的男人
I like all these men wearing helmets.
我的上帝 哦 我的...
My goodness. Oh, my...
公主 没事了 公主 我在这
Princess. It's OK, Princess. I'm here.
谈谈掉下的假腿吧
Talk about getting off on the wrong foot.
典礼正式结束
The ceremony has officially ended.
你不应该藏起来
You shouldn't hide.
这样只会招来更多的闲言闲语
It only makes them gossip more.
你想干吗?
What do you want?
现在我不需要这个了
I don't need this right now.
公主 对不起 女皇驾到
Princess, excuse me. The queen has arrived.
好的
Yes.
尼古拉斯
Nicholas.
我让你有些失望了吗?
Am I going to be disappointed in you?
我要离开了 你打算送送我吗?
I'm just leaving. You going to come and see me off?
我的工作是保护皇室 保证没有人能够伤害到它
My job is to protect the crown, to make sure no harm comes to the crown.
我想整个国家都了解 你对皇室的情感是多么的阿谀奉承
I think the entire country understands how well you cater for the crown's emotions.
可能吧
Perhaps.
但是在你的眼里有了
But it's in your eyes.
你忘了一些东西
You forgot something.
尼古拉斯 我... 我想问你一个问题
Nicholas, l... I want to ask you a question.
当然 殿下
Of course, Your Majesty.
为什么你反对米娅公主当女皇呢?
Why are you so against Princess Mia being queen?
嗯 我的舅舅认为米娅公主不了解这里的人民
Well, my uncle feels that Princess Mia doesn't know the people.
那么你认为你了解这里的人民吗?
And you feel you do know the people?
我是一个真正的基诺维亚人
I am a true Genovian.
可是 我开始感觉她可以成为一个很好的统治者
Well, I happen to feel that she'll make a great ruler.
她很聪明 敏感 富有同情心
She's terribly bright, sensitive, caring.
如果她不了解她的子民 怎么能够统治他们呢?
How can one rule the people if they do not know the people?
说的好 这是一个很好的问题
Touche. That's a very good question.
这看上去可以吃
Looks good enough to eat.
你的孙子们 莉莉 夏洛特和山姆怎么样了?
How are your grandchildren, Lily, Charlotte and Sam?
他们都很好 谢谢您还记得
They're wonderful. Thank you for remembering.
你好吗? 很高兴见到你
How are you? Good to see you.
你的猎犬怎么样了? 毛利 对吗?
How's your dachshund? Maury, right?
他很好 您去年夏天见过他后 还记得他?
He is great. You remember him from last summer?
米娅干的很好
Mia's doing well.
米娅
Mia.
我们都认识对方
We acknowledge each other.
讨厌
Yuck.
让我们从这儿走
Let's go this way.
没人能追上我
No more straggling for me.
你好 我是安德鲁・雅格布
Hello. I'm Andrew Jacoby.
你好
Hello.
爱莉莎和我刚刚在讨论最新的成就
Elissa and I were just discussing her latest achievement.
为什么不说说呢? 你是个很令人惊奇的女人
Why not brag? You're an amazing woman.
爱莉莎 恭喜你
Elissa, congratulations.
安德鲁获得了牛津大学人类学的博士学位
Andrew has a PhD in anthropology from Oxford.
安德鲁 你想喝点什么吗?
Andrew, would you like to get a drink?
我要让你知道我很喜欢安德鲁
I will have you know that I am very attracted to Andrew.
哦 显然
Well, obviously.
我没有听到你说爱
I didn't hear you mention love.
他要用他的余生来娶你
He's got to spend the rest of his life married to you.
我讨厌你
I loathe you.
等等 你在干吗? 你怎么了?
Wait. What are you doing? What is wrong with you?
你不能随便的吻别人
You can't just go around kissing people.
不! 别想把我搞糊涂
No! Stop trying to confuse me.
你刚刚在想让我喜欢你 好让我不想嫁给安德鲁
You're just trying to make me like you so that I won't want to marry Andrew
你知道吗? 我有个主意 一个很经典的主意
You know what? I have an idea. I have a brilliant idea.
为什么你不呆在水下 让我数100万下呢?
Why don't you go underwater and I'll count to a million?
是的
Yes.
低调
Hushed tones.
人们都看着我们 我们要以一种高标准来要求自己
People look up to us, and we're held to higher standards of behavior.
哦 我想说是这样的
Oh, I would say so.
晚安
Good night.
晚安 奶奶
Good night, Grandmother.
好了 毛瑞斯 这里只有你和我了
Well, Maurice, it's just you and l.
还是我也让你生气了吗?
Or are you upset with me too?
基诺维亚皇家警卫 集合
Royal Guard of Genovia, fall in.
为什么你像那样说话?
Why do you talk like that?
我们都像那样说话怎么样?
What if we all talked like that?
干的非常好 莉莉小姐
That was very nicely done, Miss Lilly.
最漂亮的小姐正在开斯坦车
The prettiest girl is riding in the Stang.
旗子? 欢迎
Flag? Welcome.
谢谢 我可不是摇旗狂
Thank you, I am not a waving aficionado.
但是我想摇我们的国旗
But I will wave our national flag
旗子?
Flag?
今天感觉怎么样 亲爱的?
How do you feel today, my dear?
老实说 乔 不太好
Honestly, Joe, not that great.
那么 如果你叫我乔依的话会不会好些?
Well, would you feel better if you called me Joey?
不能让基诺维亚的人民等太久
Can't keep the people of Genovia waiting any longer.
独立日快乐 基诺维亚!
Happy lndependence Day, Genovia!
我们在基诺维亚的首都派鲁斯介绍这个盛大大的年度游行
Here we are in Pyrus, capital of Genovia, for the big annual parade.
他们来了
Here they come.
这是首相莫塔斯 阔步走来
There's Prime Minister Motaz, strutting his stuff.
基诺维亚 基诺维亚
Genovia, Genovia
人们从基诺维亚各地赶来
People are coming from all over Genovia.
公主现在要干什么呢?
What's the princess going to do now?
你好 你叫什么名字?
Hello. What's your name?
卡罗莱娜
Carolina.
那么你又叫什么呢?
And what are your names?
对不起 这些孩子是?
Excuse me. These children are?
卡罗莱娜
Carolina.
你今天愿意做公主么?
Would you like to be a princess today?
不行 我太小了 真的太小了
I can't, I'm too little. Too piccola,
哦 不 因为我已经宣布了今天任何人都可以成为公主
Oh, no. Because I declare that anyone can be a princess today.
其实 你们为什么不都戴上头冠呢?
In fact, why don't you all take tiaras?
所有人? 把所有免费的头冠都给他们?
All? Give them all free tiaras?
你不能在挥手的时候还把大拇指放进嘴里
You won't be able to wave with your thumb in your mouth.
我们可以让世上有更多的王子
We could always use more princes in the world.
好的 那么...
OK, so...
要成为一位公主 你首先要相信自己是一位公主
To be a princess, you have to believe that you are a princess.
你要像你心中所想的公主那样走路
You've got to walk the way you think a princess would walk.
想象自己很高 保持微笑 挥手 玩的开心点
So think tall, you gotta smile,  and wave, and just have fun.
啊 她在让孩子们融入自己 多迷人啊
Ah, she's letting the children join her. How charming.
为公主击鼓
Give the princess a drumroll.
齐步...
Forward...
走!
march!
记住 你是公主
Just remember, you are a princess.
我要张开翅膀学会飞翔
I'll spread my wings and I'll learn how to fly
我会尽力去触摸天空
I'll do what it takes 'til I touch the sky
但是我不会忘了我爱的人
But I won't forget all the ones that I love
我要冒险
I'll take a risk
抓住机会 改变自己
Take a chance, make a change
感谢米娅公主带给我们的特殊惊喜
Thanks to Princess Mia's special surprise.
希望她今后的日子越来越好
May the rest of your day be sunny-side up.
我为我有两个住所而他们却一间没有 而感到内疚
I feel guilty having two homes while they have none.
克劳里爵士 你的兄弟呢?
Lord Crawley, how is your brother doing?
嗯 我已经聘请他来当这个工程的设计师
Well, I've hired him to be the architect on the project.
先生们
Gentlemen.
我希望您能对这些计划提出意见
I look forward to getting your notes on these plans.
女王同意这个计划 我打算整个过程都要察看
The queen approves of the plan,  and I intend to see it through.
好了 先生们 我想你们不会花太长时间筹到钱 是么?
Now, gentlemen, I don't think it'll take too long to raise the money. Do you?
我们在弄舞厅里的斜坡
We're setting up the ramp in the ballroom.
好的
OK.
我的问候是无关紧要的
My hello's insignificant.
我是想告诉你你在游行时候的举动 给我留下了很深的印象
I wanted to tell you that I was very impressed by what you did at the parade.
谢谢
Thank you.
我要举行一个睡袍派对
I'm having a slumber party.
恭喜建造儿童中心
Congratulations on the children's center.
兰妮 斯贵吉 快点
Lenny, Squiggy, zip it.
莉莉? 公主们马上到了
Lilly? The princesses are arriving.
你好 洛林公主
Hello, Princess Lorraine.
哦
Oh.
嗨 夏洛特
Hi, Charlotte.
哦
Oh.
现在 我也给你们准备了一个礼物
now, I have a present for you.
派对就要开始
Time to get the party started
让我们跳吧
Let's bounce
因为我们都想这样
'Cause we all want to
让我们跳吧
Let's bounce
玩的多开心
Gonna have some fun
让我们跳吧
Let's bounce
派对开始了
Get the party on
让我们跳吧
Let's bounce
从黄昏到黎明
From dusk 'til dawn
让我们大喊
Let's shout
你知道我们要跳起来
You know we gotta make it bounce
我准备好了 宝贝
I'm ready, baby
让我们跳吧
Let's bounce
我想我还有些牛奶和饼干在房间里 奥利维亚
I think I'll just have some milk and cookies in my room, Olivia.
我也那样做过 但是有一点不同
I did it too, you know. But a little differently.
费利克斯?
Felix?
但是我这一生飞行过很多次
But I've done a lot of flying in my time.
她真的要这样做么?
Is she really going to do this?
可以么?
May l?
哈!
Ha!
早上起来这么早
Rise up so early in the morn
女仆 做你的家务活去吧
Maids, go do your chores
女王殿下就会为我们唱一首歌
Her Majesty may sing us a song.
谢谢 不
Thank you, no.
女王很少唱卡拉OK的
Queens rarely do karaoke.
奶奶 来吧 就唱你在我18岁生日派对上唱的那首歌
Grandma, come on. The song you sang at my 18th-birthday party.
米娅有一部CD 你可以随着一起唱
Mia had a CD made,  so you can sing along.
克拉丽斯 克拉丽斯
Clarisse, Clarisse,
克拉丽斯 克拉丽斯 克拉丽斯...
Clarisse, Clarisse, Clarisse...
有些女孩很漂亮 有些快乐又健康
Some girls are fair,  some are jolly and fit.
每个人都是一件珠宝 有着独特的光泽
Each one's a jewel, with a singular shine
亲爱的小女孩 深深的祝福你
Dear little girl, you are terribly blessed
但是我最爱的是你金子般的心灵
But it's your heart of gold I love the best
它都会是你最高的荣誉
lt'll always be your crowning glory
你做了什么?
What did you do?
嗯 我可能是在电脑上改变了一点旋律
Well, I might have tweaked it a little bit on my computer.
但是我不知道怎么做这种事
But I don't know how to do this sort of thing.
有些人看起来没有缺点
Some seem to have no faults
我?
Me?
继续
Go on.
那是你最高的荣誉
That will be your crowning glory
格雷琴 热水
Gretchen, hot water.
而且她真心在乎基诺维亚
And she really cares about Genovia.
可能...
Maybe...
嗯 如果让她来治理这个国家也许会不错
Well, maybe it wouldn't be so bad if she ran the country.
你疯了么?
Are you mad?
毕竟我们付出了努力 就这样无为而终?
After all the effort that we have put in,  to end up with nothing?
啊
Ah.
你爱上她了
You've fallen in love with her.
不
No.
不 叔叔 我要问的是...
No, Uncle, all that I'm asking...
我耗尽精力要让你当上国王
I put in the effort to make you a king,
哦 但是你在乎她
Oh, but you care for her.
叔叔 我只是想我们不要再对她使坏了 就是这样
Uncle, I just want us to stop trying to sabotage her. That's all.
好的 如果这就是你真正想要的
All right. If that's what you really want.
我只是想让你高兴 我的孩子
I just want your happiness, my boy.
去找她
Go to her.
祝贺她
Congratulate her.
告诉她我们认输了
And tell her that we surrender.
谢谢你 叔叔
Thank you, Uncle.
请找埃尔希・肯特沃希
Elsie Kentworthy, please.
你肯定我没有烧伤你?
Are you sure I didn't burn you?
只是袖子有些烧焦 看
You just sort of seared the sleeve. Look.
对不起
Sorry.
看那边
Look over there.
我只是想和尼古拉斯说会话
I just want to talk to Nicholas for a second.
好的
OK.
你为什么不去把莉莉介绍给你的父母呢?
Why don't you go introduce Lilly to your parents?
是的 我很希望能认识苏珊和阿诺德
Yeah, I'd love to meet Susan and Arnold.
我们可以一起吃那些可口的三明治
We can have those tasty finger sandwiches together.
需要帮忙么?
Would you like some help?
他不是她要嫁的那个人 是么?
He's not the one she's marrying, is he?
肘放下来 放下一点
Elbow down. Just a bit.
用你的嘴当锚
Use your mouth as an anchor.
好
Good.
这只手放松
Relax this hand.
噢
Oh.
感觉如何?
How did that feel?
好极了
Wonderful.
你要走了?
You're leaving?
我想应该是我平静退出的时候了
I think it's time I bowed out gracefully.
你呢?
Don't you?
再见
Goodbye.
米娅
Mia.
在我走之前我能再见你一面么?
Could I see you one more time before I go?
尼古拉斯 我像一只鹰一样被监视着
Nicholas, I'm watched like a hawk.
公主 公主
Princess, Princess.
看到了吧?
See?
我会找到办法的
I'll find a way.
嗯 没什么 我只是应该看护着你
Um, nothing. I'm just supposed to watch you.
我得检查一下乐队挑选的如何了
I have to check the orchestra selections.
你考虑过我们么?
Have you been thinking about us?
是的
Yes, I have.
我知道了
I see.
不 约瑟夫 你必须知道我要说什么
No, Joseph. You had to know what I was going to say.
米娅现在比以前任何时候都更需要我
Mia needs me now more than ever before.
你从来就不只是我的女王 克拉丽斯
You were never just my queen, Clarisse.
你是我想共度一生的人
You were the someone that I wanted to spend the rest of my life with.
但是 如果你希望我首先把你当成我的女王...
But, if you prefer that I see you first and foremost as my queen...
殿下
Your Majesty.
你的床铺好了 殿下
Your bed is turned down, Your Highness.
噢 好的 你们随便吧 女士们
Oh. Well, enjoy yourselves, ladies.
不要再行屈膝礼了
No more curtsy.
我们去吃晚饭了
We're going to supper.
谢谢
Thank you.
尼古拉斯
Nicholas.
尼古拉斯 你在干什么?
Nicholas, what are you doing?
莴苣姑娘 莴苣姑娘 你的头发如此美丽
Rapunzel, Rapunzel, with hair so fine.
从窗户出来 顺着藤爬下来
Come out your window,  climb down the vine.
他想干什么?
What does he want?
他想让我从藤上爬下去
He wants me to climb down the vine.
我一直喜欢在阴影中的男人
I always like a man in shades.
进来 进来 我正想出去
Come in, come in. I was just about to leave.
我的脚卡住了
My foot is stuck.
噢 那是什么?
Oh, what was that?
雅克兄弟 雅克兄弟
Frre Jacques, Frre Jacques
晨钟响了 晨钟响了
Sonnez les matines, sonnez les matines
我们在派对上没有看到真是可惜啊
What a pity we missed it at the party.
但是每个人都可以了解你的愿望
But anyone can see your desires.
没有人知道你心里想什么
No one knows what's in your heart.
我学校里有考试的时候 我就装作生病
I used to pretend I was sick when I had a test in school.
我特别害怕水母
I am deathly afraid of jellyfish.
我还想
I still want to.
温柔的爱我
Love me tender
甜蜜的爱我
Love me sweet
不要让我走
Never let me go
早上好
Good morning.
我们整晚都呆在外边
We stayed out all night.
我想可能是渔民吧
He's probably some fisherman, I suppose.
拿着一个摄像机?
With a video camera?
不 米娅 我根本不知道那个男的是谁
No, Mia. I have no idea who that man is.
米娅 我和这件事根本无关 我发誓
Mia, I have nothing to do with this. I swear.
早上好 亲爱的
Good morning, my love.
我知道有点早 但是我一直在想
I know it's a little early,  but I've been thinking.
最近事情的确压力很大
Things have been so pressured lately.
莉莉?
Lilly?
早安 殿下
Good morning, Your Majesty.
米娅
Mia.
现在对米娅公主来说相当于从煎锅 出来又跳进了火里
It's out of the frying pan and into the fire for Princess Mia,
我应该告诉她应该怎么做她的鸡蛋...
I'd like to tell her what she can do with her eggs...
莉莉
Lilly.
那么?
So?
我被耍了
I got played.
啊-哈
A-ha.
安德鲁 等一下 我向你发誓什么也没有发生
Andrew, please wait. I promise you nothing happened.
我还是觉得我们的婚姻是非常好的
I still think this marriage is a good idea.
米娅
Mia.
女王不会赞成监视的
The queen would not approve of spying.
啊
Ah.
那么?
So?
我也是
Me too.
我们要指出一些东西
We will figure something out.
米娅
Mia.
你选择了我
You chose me.
没有秘密
No privacy.
你选择了我 我接受了
You chose me, and I accepted.
一个绅士从不收回他的话
And a gentleman never backs out on his word.
我们要...
We are going to...
谢谢
Thank you.
今天我就要结婚了
I'm getting married today.
她今天就要结婚了 毛瑞斯
She's getting married today, Maurice.
殿下 我们迟到了很多
Your Highness, we're running very late.
奶奶说女王从来不迟到 只是其他人来早了
Grandma says the queen is never late,  everyone else is simply early.
看 这就是我所说的壁橱
Now, this is what I call a closet.
结婚就是做回你自己 只不过是和其他人一起
Being married is about being yourself,  only with someone else.
谢谢 妈妈
Thanks, Mom.
保罗又回来了 把毛毛虫变成蝴蝶
Paolo is back to turn a caterpillar into a butterfly.
给新娘的婚礼装
A wedding look for the bride.
我看起来像个驼鹿
I look like a moose.
我看起来像一只狮子狗
I look like a poodle.
格雷琴? 我找不到我的手套了
Gretchen? I can't find my gloves.
你去吧 我想我还是不去比较好
You go on. I think it would be better if I didn't go to the wedding.
我的孩子
My boy.
我会尽力抓住带子的
I'll try to catch the garter.
皇家马车就要到了
The royal carriage approaches.
他在等什么
He's up to something.
他非常高兴 你没有去参加婚礼
He was much too delighted that you aren't going to that wedding.
不 不 你骑自行车
No, no. You'll take the bike.
你祖父的自行车
Your grandfather's bike.
很抱歉 我叔叔的英语是从老的喜剧电影里学来的
I'm sorry. My uncle learned his English watching the old Three Stooges movies.
对不起
Sorry.
是的 嗯...
Yes, well...
你不可能相信的
You're not going to believe this.
先生!
Sir!
先生 我可以借你的马么?
Sir, may I borrow your horse?
噢 他需要我的马
Oh, he needs my horse.
我的自行车是你的了
My bike is yours.
我是一个喜欢穿黑色衣服的女孩 现在却穿着粉色衣服
I'm a girl who loves black and is wearing pink.
我只是想说 在我做这个之前...
I just wanted to say, before I do this...
很抱歉你要退休了
I'm sorry you're retiring.
你在告诫唱诗班
You're preaching to the choir.
公主?
Princess?
什么事?
Yes?
她进来的时候我们都准备好了
We're ready when she is.
我需要一两分钟
I'm going to need a minute or two.
谢谢 殿下
Thank you, Your Highness.
现在公主快速的退出走廊跑出门去了
Now the bride is moving swiftly back up the aisle and out the door.
我要给特雷弗换尿布了
I gotta change Trevor's diaper.
噢 亲爱的 米娅
Oh, my dear. Mia.
亲爱的 听我说
Darling, listen to me.
我做了选择
I made my choice.
现在我失去了我曾经深爱的唯一的男人
Now I've lost the only man I ever really loved.
米娅 我想你应该从一个女人的角度 做出选择
Mia, I want you to make your choices as a woman.
不要再和我犯同样的错误
Don't make the same mistakes I did.
现在 你可以回教堂去举行婚礼 也可以走开
Now, you can go back into that church and get married, or you can walk away.
公主又进入了教堂
The princess is reentering the church.
她沿着走廊走过来
She's walking down the aisle.
安德鲁 等等
Andrew, wait.
每个人都有发现真爱的机会 对么?
Everyone deserves the chance to find true love, right?
是的
Yes.
包括我们?
Including us?
谢谢
Thank you.
为了 为了 嗯...
For, for, uh...
现在我要做的就是告诉妈妈
Now all I have to do is tell Mummy.
我不得不告诉其他人
I have to tell everyone else.
祝你好运
Good luck.
海伦
Helen.
欢迎大家
Welcome.
因此...
So...
我今天不准备结婚了
I won't be getting married today.
坐下 坐下 可能会有晚餐
Sit. Sit. There may be a dinner.
我的奶奶在没有男人的情况下 当政了很长时间...
My grandmother has ruled without a man at her side for quite some time, and...
我想她动摇了
I think she rocks at it.
所以作为克拉丽斯女王 和鲁伯特国王的孙女...
So as the granddaughter of Queen Clarisse and King Rupert...
我请求议员们为你们的女儿考虑一下
I ask the members of parliament to think about your daughters,
你们会强迫她们去做 你们让我做的事情么?
would you force them to do what you're trying to make me do?
我相信我会成为一个伟大的女王
I believe I will be a great queen.
我从心底和灵魂深处感觉到我可以 治理好基诺维亚
I feel in my heart and soul that I can rule Genovia.
我...我爱基诺维亚
I... I love Genovia.
如果不是 你们觉得我会穿着一身婚纱站在这么?
Do you think that I would be up here in a wedding dress if I didn't?
我站在这 是准备做你们的女王的
I stand here, ready to take my place as your queen.
米娅万岁!
Viva Mia!
每次...
Every time...
法律明确指出 一个未婚女子不可以成为女王
The law clearly states an unmarried woman cannot be queen.
不 没有
No, there is not.
女士们先生们 米娅公主才是应该继位的人
Ladies and gentlemen, it is Princess Mia who should have the crown.
她聪明 有同情心
She's bright, and she is caring.
更重要的是 她有远见
But more importantly, she has a vision.
听她的 她会带领我们进入21世纪
Listen to her. She'll lead us into the 21 st century.
还有 想想她在我们的邮票上会看起来多可爱
And besides, just think how lovely she'll look on our postage stamp.
看起来在邮票上可爱?
Lovely on a postage stamp?
尼古拉斯 尼古拉斯!
Nicholas. Nicholas!
尼古拉斯 我不能让你把这一切都给那个女孩
Nicholas, I cannot have you giving all this up just for a girl.
这发生了什么?
What is happening here?
坐下
Sit down.
做一个提议
Make a motion.
啊
Ah.
有人赞成我的提议么?
Will anyone second my motion?
不 不 不...温柔点 柔和点
No, not, not... Soften. Soften.
好
Good.
我赞成提议
I second the motion.
我想你要是留胡子会棒极了
I think you'd look marvelous with a mustache.
是
Aye.
通过
The ayes have it.
祝贺你 公主
Congratulations, Princess.
殿下?
Your Majesty?
嗯?
Hm?
奶奶?
Grandma?
噢 呃...
Oh, uh...
噢 夏洛特
Oh, Charlotte.
好
Well.
约瑟夫?
Joseph?
殿下?
Your Majesty.
亲爱的约瑟夫
Dear Joseph.
嗯 我想你从没问过
Well, I thought you'd never ask.
施德?
Shades?
我要结婚了
I'm going to a wedding.
让我进去
Let me in,
把我放下来 把我放下来!
Put me down, Put me down!
我知道几乎没怎么通知 但是你们都身着盛装
I know it was short notice,  but you were all dressed.
尊敬的大教主 我想让这个男人做我的丈夫 如果你同意的话
My Lord Archbishop, I would like to take this man as my husband, if you please.
我们都来到这是为了另一个婚礼...
We have come together for a different wedding...
我宣布 你们是夫妻了
I pronounce you man and wife.
你可以吻新娘
You may kiss the bride.
在皇宫的某个地方 米娅公主正在为仪式作准备
Somewhere in the palace, Princess Mia's getting ready for the ceremony
你要说什么 胖路易?
So what do you say, Fat Louie?
你的选择是什么 年轻人?
What is your dilemma, young man?
你给我的餐桌准备了鸡肉么?
Do you have a chicken for my table?
不 没有 我的厨房没有鸡肉了
No. No, my kitchen is out of chickens.
啊
Ah.
米娅
Mia.
左 右 左
Left, right, left.
左 左...
Left, left...
左 右 左
Left, right, left.
左 左...
Left, left...
左 右 左
Left, right, left.
左 左...
Left, left...
我听说你要回柏克利完成学业
I heard you're going back to Berkeley to finish up graduate school.
你听的没错
You heard right.
我能在加利福尼亚给你打电话么?
May I call you in California?
我想我不用电话就能听见你 但是 呃...
I think I can hear you without a phone, but, uh...
麻雀起飞了
Sparrow is taking off.
老鹰最后一次起飞
The eagle is flying for the last time.
我庄严的许诺 我会这样做的
I solemnly promise so to do.
基诺维亚
Genovia
我们自己的土地
The land I call my own
但是 不用担心
Don't worry,though
你相信吗？
Are you believing?
我在寻找答案
I've been looking for the answer
现在我终于知道了
But now I know what I didn't know